so let's see what is memory consistency
and how it differs from coherence what
coherence does is define the order of
accesses observable by different threads
if these accesses go to the same memory
location or to the same address
coherence is needed in order to share
data without coherence at read is
allowed to modify memory location while
another thread is allowed to read
forever the old value of that location
in which case we cannot really write
shared memory programs at work an
important thing about coherence however
is that it defines the order of accesses
to the same address it does not say
anything about accesses that go to
different location and that is what
memory consistency is about it defines
the order of accesses to different
addresses so the big question now before
we get into consistencies does this even
matter if we guarantee that when I write
to something all the other cores get to
see it and that happens for every
address as in I right away somebody sees
what I wrote I wrote to be somebody sees
what they wrote what can change about
the order of accesses to different
addresses and how does that even matter
if I need to maintain this